What is the greatest threat to life on our planet?
我们星球上的生命而言，最大的威胁是什么呢？
Is it climate change?
是气候变化吗？
Is it a shortage of food or water?
是食物或水的短缺吗？
Or could a bigger danger come from further afield: from space?
又或者，一个更大的危险可能来自更遥远的地方：太空？
We're not talking about an invasion by little green men here.
我们这里说的可不是小绿人的入侵。
Instead, how about the prospect of being hit by a gigantic meteorite, zapped by lethal cosmic rays or fried by the deadly energy of an erupting star?
相反，其他可能性又如何？比如被一颗巨大的陨石撞击、被致命的宇宙射线摧毁，或者被一颗恒星爆炸的致命能量炙烤。
It wouldn't be the first time.
这可不是第一次了。
Good old planet Earth has had a rough ride over the last 3.7 billion years, with some spectacularly devastating events.
在过去的37亿年里，古老而美好的地球经历了一段艰难的历程，发生了一些极其具有毁灭性的事件。
The most famous mass extinction was 66 million years ago, when it's widely believed a meteorite killed off the dinosaurs.
最著名的大规模灭绝事件发生在6600万年前，人们普遍认为是一颗陨石导致了恐龙的灭绝。
A 110-mile-wide crater in Mexico with the same geological age supports this theory.
墨西哥一个有着相同地质年代、宽110英里的陨石坑支持了这一理论。
Believe it or not, this wasn't the most brutal episode in our planet's history.
信不信由你，这并不是我们星球历史上最残酷的事件。
That was when a staggering 96% of life was wiped out at the end of the Permian period, 252 million years ago.
最残酷的是在2.52亿年前的二叠纪末期，惊人的96%的生命灭绝了。
Scientists don't know for sure why this happened, but any potential explanations carry with them the grim possibility that similar events could happen again.
科学家们不确定这是为什么，但任何可能的解释都伴随着类似事件可能再次发生的令人沮丧的可能性。
For example, some experts believe that our Sun has a very dense, dim twin star which is too far away to observe directly.
例如，一些专家认为我们的太阳有一颗非常致密、昏暗的伴星，它距离太远，无法直接观测到。
This sleeping giant, dubbed the "Death Star", could distort the paths of orbiting chunks of icy rock and hurl them towards the rest of the Solar System.
这个被称为“死亡之星”的沉睡巨人，可能会扭曲绕轨道运行的冰岩块的路径，并将它们抛向太阳系的其他地方。
Is this what happened 252 million years ago?
这就是2.52亿年前发生的事情吗？
Or is there instead, perhaps, a distant, ninth planet in our Solar System which pulls in passing comets and sends them hurtling our way?
或者，也许在我们的太阳系中有一颗遥远的第九颗行星，它吸引路过的彗星，并将它们朝着我们的方向猛冲过来？
If that isn't enough to put you off your breakfast, then consider what's happening to our friend, the Sun.
如果这还不足以让你没了吃早餐的胃口，那就想想我们的朋友——太阳正在发生什么吧。
The star that has given us the warmth to sustain life is gradually turning into a deadly foe.
这颗给予我们温暖以维持生命的恒星正逐渐变成一个致命的敌人。
Like all stars, it is slowly dying, burning through its energy supplies.
和所有恒星一样，它正在慢慢走向死亡，燃尽自身的能量储备。
As it does so, it expands, and in about 2 billion years it will have grown so much that the heat will make life on planet Earth unbearable.
随着这个过程的进行，它会膨胀，大约20亿年后，它会变得非常巨大，其热量将使地球上的生命无法承受。
While all this sounds a little macabre, take comfort from the fact that the chance of being hit by a giant interstellar projectile is incredibly slim, and that 2 billion years is a very long time.
虽然这一切听起来有点可怕，但可以感到安慰的是，被一颗巨大的星际抛射物击中的几率极其渺茫，而且20亿年是一段非常漫长的时间。
And there's another thing: if the dinosaurs had not snuffed it when they did, it's extremely unlikely that human beings would have had the chance to evolve at all.
还有一件事：如果恐龙当时没有灭绝，人类极有可能根本就没有机会进化。